This task is about the mathematical representation
of Petri Nets and the graphical representation
of Petri Nets.
And more specifically, it's about getting
the mathematical representation of the Petri
Nets from the graphical representation.
So, if we're given a Petri Net which is represented
here, and now we should give the mathematical
representation of exactly this Petri Net.
And for this, we first of all need to define
what the Petri Net consists of.
Therefore, we've got the five tuples.
We say that the net is the five tuple of the
places of the transitions of the ingoing edges
to transitions of their outgoing edges, and
the initial marking, m0.
And now we are required to define these parameters
most specifically.
So we say, this is our Petri Net, where the
places S are the set of all the places that
we've got, and in this case, they have three,
and these are s1 to s3.
And then we've got transitions, the set of
transitions is also all the transitions that
we’ve got here.
So, in this case, there are four transitions
and these are t1, t2, t3 and t4.
And we are required to give the ingoing set
for the transition.
So, the mapping for the edges, that means
the ingoing transition, we can define it like
this, that we say the ingoing edge for t1
from.
And now we define the places where we have
got edges to t1 in this case, there's just
a single one from s1.
So, we have just s1 definition for the ingoing
edge to t1.
And there is none when we look for a label
here, so we've got one here.
Then we continue for t2.
And we've gotten an edge also, that's why
we have here s2 which is where the edge is
coming from.
And again, there's no labels, so we've got
one.
Then we continue with t3, there's also an
edge, so we write t3 as well.
And it's coming from s3 and there's no label.
So, again one and then we've got t4 and there
are two edges so we can have one t4 coming
from s1 and there's no label again.
Again one, and another for t5 and from s2 with
no label again, so having one.
For all other pairs
of transitions
t and places s, it shall hold
that t of s is zero.
This means there are no other ingoing edges
to any other transitions or any of those transitions.
They're just the ones that we defined and
no other ones.
And now, after we've defined this for the
incoming edges, we continue with the outgoing
edges.
And for t1, we have an outgoing edge going
to s2 and there we have no weights defined,
this means we have the weight of one.
We continue for t2, it has an outgoing edge
and I forgot the dot here which is important.
Marking it as outgoing edge here on the
right hand side, this one goes to s3 and again
no labels, so the weight of one.
Then we have got t3, it has also an edge
outgoing to s1 and it has again no labels.
So, one is the weight and then we have an
outgoing edge from t4 going to s3.
And here, we have a weight of two, that means
we write this weight of two.
And again, we write that for all other pairs
of transitions t and places s.
It holds
that t with outgoing edge to s is zero.
That means that we have no other outgoing
edges from these transitions but those defined.
And furthermore, for our tuple, we require
m0. So we write m0 and then
we check all of these places for what
m0 will look like.
So for m0 of s1, it has one token.
The same goes for m0 of s2.
So there we have one.
So, for m0 of s1 and s2 is one token each
and for s3 there, we have no token.
So, m0 of s3 is zero.
Now we have defined the complete five tuple
for our Petri Net and thus, we have defined
the Petri Net within the mathematical representation.